<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://mahshidbaharifar.github.io/DSAIlab/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://mahshidbaharifar.github.io/DSAIlab/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-16T23:20:53+00:00</updated><id>https://mahshidbaharifar.github.io/DSAIlab/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DSAI</title><subtitle>Developing mathematically grounded AI methods to model complex dynamical systems and solve mathematical problems.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">PhD Opening for Our Project</title><link href="https://mahshidbaharifar.github.io/DSAIlab/2024/10/15/example-post-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PhD Opening for Our Project" /><published>2024-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-16T23:19:30+00:00</updated><id>https://mahshidbaharifar.github.io/DSAIlab/2024/10/15/example-post-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mahshidbaharifar.github.io/DSAIlab/2024/10/15/example-post-3.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;">
  <img src="images/new-position-image.png" alt="group image photo" style="width: 500px; height: auto;" />
</div>

<p>We are excited to announce a <strong>PhD position opening</strong> in our BMBF-funded Independent Research Group at Heidelberg University, Germany. With generous funding of approximately €1.31 million from the Federal Ministry of Education and Research (BMBF), our team focuses on cutting-edge research at the intersection of Artificial Intelligence and mathematics.</p>

<p>The project, titled <strong>“Operator-Based Training of Recurrent Neural Networks for Time Series Analysis and Modeling of Complex Dynamical Systems,”</strong> aims to develop innovative approaches to train Recurrent Neural Networks (RNNs) for analyzing and modeling complex, real-world dynamical systems. The research involves applying AI and machine learning techniques to address challenges in time series analysis, advancing the understanding of complex data-driven systems.</p>

<h3 id="what-we-offer">What We Offer:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Full-time funded PhD position as part of a dynamic, interdisciplinary research group.</li>
  <li>Access to Heidelberg University’s world-class resources and research facilities.</li>
  <li>Opportunities to collaborate with leading experts in AI, mathematics, and data science.</li>
  <li>A supportive environment for innovation and professional growth.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-we-are-looking-for">What We Are Looking For:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>A strong academic background in mathematics, computer science, or a related field.</li>
  <li>Experience with machine learning, deep learning, and programming (preferably Python).</li>
  <li>Interest in time series analysis, dynamical systems, and AI model development.</li>
  <li>Motivation to contribute to groundbreaking research in the field of Artificial Intelligence.</li>
</ul>

<p>This is an excellent opportunity for a highly motivated individual to contribute to an innovative project while advancing their career in the rapidly evolving field of AI. Join us in pushing the boundaries of machine learning applications and solving real-world challenges!</p>

<p>For more details and application instructions, please <a href="mailto:mahshidbahari@gmail.com">contact us</a> or visit our <a href="https://mahshidbaharifar.github.io/DSAIlab/">project page</a>.</p>

<hr />]]></content><author><name>Zahra Monfared</name></author><category term="machine learning" /><category term="RNN" /><category term="PhD Position" /><category term="Time Series Analysis" /><category term="AI" /><category term="Dynamical Systems" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://mahshidbaharifar.github.io/DSAIlab/images/new-position-image1.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://mahshidbaharifar.github.io/DSAIlab/images/new-position-image1.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Our Group has been established</title><link href="https://mahshidbaharifar.github.io/DSAIlab/2024/09/01/example-post-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our Group has been established" /><published>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-16T23:19:30+00:00</updated><id>https://mahshidbaharifar.github.io/DSAIlab/2024/09/01/example-post-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mahshidbaharifar.github.io/DSAIlab/2024/09/01/example-post-1.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;">
  <img src="images/group-image-corner.jpg" alt="group image photo" style="width: 500px; height: auto;" />
</div>

<p>We are excited to announce the establishment of our BMBF-funded Independent Research Group in the field of Artificial Intelligence at Heidelberg University, Germany. With a generous funding of approximately €1.31 million from the Federal Ministry of Education and Research (BMBF), our team comprises one Postdoc, two PhD candidates, and a student assistant, in addition to my own position. The project, titled “Operator-Based Training of Recurrent Neural Networks for Time Series Analysis and Modeling of Complex Dynamical Systems,” aims to develop innovative approaches to train Recurrent Neural Networks (RNNs) for analyzing and modeling complex, real-world dynamical systems. Our interdisciplinary research focuses on leveraging AI to address challenges in time series analysis, pushing the boundaries of machine learning applications in this field. Stay tuned for updates as we progress on this exciting journey!</p>]]></content><author><name>Zahra Monfared</name></author><category term="machine learning" /><category term="RNN" /><category term="Time Series Data" /><category term="AI" /><category term="Dynamical System" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://mahshidbaharifar.github.io/DSAIlab/images/group-image-corner.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://mahshidbaharifar.github.io/DSAIlab/images/group-image-corner.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>